$( document ).ready(function() {
  var index = 0;

  $(".theAnswer p").addClass("hide");

  showContent(index);

  $("#nextCard").on("click", function() {
    $(".theAnswer p").addClass("hide");
    if(index === flashCards.length - 1) {
      index = 0;
    }
    index++;
    showContent(index);
  });

  $("#showCard").on("click", function() {
    $(".theAnswer p").removeClass("hide");
  });

  $("#knowCard").on("click", function() {
    flashCards.splice(index, 1)
    showContent(index);
  });

});

/*********************************************************************
* The Deck Of Cards (an array filled with object & Key: Value pairs) *
**********************************************************************/

var flashCards = [
  {
    question: "List the 5 JS data types",
    answer: "Numbers, Strings, Booleans, Undefined, Null"
  },
  {
    question: "We store data types in...",
    answer: "variables"
  },
  {
    question: "What is the meaning of dynamic",
    answer: "a variable can switch between data types."
  },
  {
    question: "What does Modulus do?",
    answer: "Returns the remainder of a division operation."
  },
  {
    question: "What does NaN mean?",
    answer: "Not a number"
  },
  {
    question: "What function can you use to test whether a value is a valid number using?",
    answer: "isNaN function"
  },
  {
    question: "What are arrays?",
    answer: "Ordered collection of related data types."
  },
  {
    question: "How are arrays orginized?",
    answer: "by index."
  },
  {
    question: "How are Objects orginized?",
    answer: "Properties are stored as key-value pairs."
  },
  {
    question: "Variable names should be named how?",
    answer: "named using camelCase lettering."
  },
  {
    question: "whatâ€™s a function?",
    answer: "Code wraped in a value, that can be re-used."
  },
  {
    question: "What's a method?",
    answer: "Methods are functions that are attached to some object."
  },
  {
    question: "What is the programming interface for HTML called?",
    answer: "The Document Object Model."
  },
  {
    question: "Each web page loaded in the browser has its own...",
    answer: "document object."
  },
  {
    question: "Using JS what method would you use select a tag that contained an ID?",
    answer: ".getElementById"
  },
  {
    question: "How would you listen for an event?",
    answer: "the addEventListener method"
  },
  {
    question: "List all the falsey values",
    answer: "false, zero, empty string, null, undefined, NaN"
  },
  {
    question: "The mechanism that alows you to compare values?",
    answer: "comparison operators."
  },
  {
    question: "These 'things' allow you to take several paths within a program?",
    answer: "conditionals."
  },
]

/***************************************************
* Additional page functionality (a.k.a functions!) *
****************************************************/

function showContent(index) {

  var cardsLeft = (flashCards.length);
  var content = flashCards[index];
  var question = content.question;
  var answer = content.answer;

  $(".trackCards .cardsLeft").html("Cards Left: " + cardsLeft);
  $(".theQuestion p").html(question);
  $(".theAnswer p").html(answer);
  $(".theAnswer p").addClass("hide");
}


/****************************
* COMMENTS ON CODE SECTIONS *
*****************************/

/* 1
The code above wraps the code below and only initializes it once
the page is fully rendered and loaded, once that occurs, 'ready'
is printed to the console and the rest of the code executes. */

/* 2
This variable acts as a counter, it starts off at 0,
which is also the index for the first item in any array.
We will pass this index as an argument of the 'showQnA'
function before the .ready function ends. */

/* 3
This function call occurs once the page is completely loaded
the showQnA function fills in the appropriete data on the
index card. This data comes from the array of objects 'flashCards'
and what data is being passed depends on what the index is. */

/* 4
The code sets up an event listener using jQuery.
Since the user will only click next once the first card has been
reviewed, this code adds 1 to the index, which controls what
content will be displayed based on index's corresponding object
in 'flashCards' then calls 'showQnA' with the new index. */
